What do you know about Stepan Andreevich
Что вы знаете о степане андреевиче
Bandera,
бандере у
the Anglo-Saxons,
англосаксы
and the Slavs
а славяне
and the Chinese, roughly
и китайцы грубо
speaking Hello Hello,
говоря Здравствуйте Здравствуйте
look I'm asking people from the Russian
смотрите Я у людей из Российской
Federation What do you know about
Федерации спрашиваю Что вы знаете о
Stepan Andreevich Bandera
степане андреевиче бандере
[applause]
[аплодисменты]
many know, for example Well, for example
мно знаем например Ну например
Tell me,
Расскажите
yes Well, for example, that Stepan Andreevich
да Ну например то что Степан Андреевич
Bandera is not  was a hero of
Бандера не был героем
Ukraine So what else do you know about him
Украины Так что вы о нём знаете
that he was not in Ukraine that he was in a concentration camp he
ещё что Украине не был что в концлагере
was in a German concentration camp what else do
сидел в немецком концлагере сидел что ещ
you know
знаете
Well somehow that's important yes I'm
Ну как-то вот а это важно да мне
interested just a lot of Russians
интересно просто очень многие россияне
will tell something about Bandera gang I
расскажет чтото про бандеру банда Мне
became interested that Russians  know about
интересно стало что россияне знают о
Bandera Well, you know that he was not in
бандере Ну вот вы знаете что он не был в
Ukraine and that he was in a German
Украине и что он сидел в немецком
concentration camp And that's all yes Well,
концлагере И всё
no, why,
да Ну нет почему же
for example, when he was born on January 1
например когда он родился 1
Yes, and there he has a lot of facts and when he
вот и там у него много фактов и когда он
died there he was 50 years old  so so what
помер там 50 лет ему было так Так что
else do
ещё
you know yes what do we know and what do we need to do than
знаете да что знаем а а что надо-то чем
what is his political  he is such an important figure
чем его политическая фигура такая важная
that Russians are still
получилось что россияне до сих пор его
afraid of him in no way
боятся ничем
and
а
why is this you understand the point here is what you
почему это вы пони дело вот в чём
understand The point is that you
понимаете Дело в том что Вы бандеру
put Bandera as if at the forefront and we are
поставили как бы ну во главе угла и мы
still asking And I have one
до сих пор спрашиваем А у меня один
question Tell me why Bandera  for example,
вопрос Скажите а почему Бандера например
not Batka Makhno, but Nestor Ivanovich
не Батька Махно вот Нестор Иванович
Makhno, for example, explain, I don’t explain,
Махно к примеру объяс смот не объясняю
look, we needed to come up with some kind of hero. And
смотрите нам нужно было какого-то героя
Kravchuk and Kuchma sat down. And they
придумать Да сел Кравчук и Кучма Да они
argued in the bathhouse and came up with the idea of ​​giving
спорили в бане и придумали что давай
Bandera to Kravchuk, who was for Makhno and Kuchma was for
бандеру Кравчук был за Махно а Кучма за
Bandera. They threw everything at him.  Chunga
бандеру всё они Кинули на Чунга
turned out to be Bandera But the question is that we
получился Бандера Но вопрос в том что мы
chose for ourselves simply Chunga Bandera Yes
себе выбрали просто на Чунга бандеру Да
and why are you afraid of him So what is it that
а почему вы его Боитесь Так что он вам
scares you so much here that you are still
такого страшно здесь что вы до сих пор
undermined by Bandera We are not
от Бандеры подрывает вас Мы не
afraid Well, you are so worried Banderas are not
боимся Ну вы так переживаете Бандеры не
Banderas the street is named Banderas
Бандеры улица Бандеры названа памятник
Bandera monument what Why are you so worried about this
Бандеры что Почему вам так это тревожат
wait wait We are not afraid of him  we
подождите подождите Мы его не боимся мы
can't understand why Bandera is your hero
не можем понять почему Бандера ваш герой
Why do you even need to understand Why
А зачем вам вообще понимать Почему
Bandera is our
Бандера наш
hero you Our neighbors Sorry I understood
герой вы Наши соседи Извините понял
what heroes of Poland you
каких героев Польши вы
know Poland No Poland your
знаете Польше Да никаких Польша ваши
neighbors What heroes of Finland do you know
соседи Какие герои Финляндии вы знаете
about Finland Marge Marge is right Yes and
о Финляндии марге марге правильно Да а
why is Marg the hero of
почему марг герой
Finland because  that he fought for her
Финляндии потому что он за неё воевал
really fought Yes so What
реально воевал Да так Какие
heroes What heroes of Kazakhstan do you
герои Какие герои Казахстана вы
know Kazakhstan they are your neighbors
знаете Казахстана это же ваши соседи
What heroes of Kazakhstan do you know No
Какие герои Казахстана вы знаете Без
idea well What heroes of Azerbaijan do
понятия хорошо Какие герои Азербайджана
you know I
вы знаете
don't know what heroes in Georgia do you
не знаю каких герои в Грузии вы
know I don't know what heroes in Mongolia do
знаете не знаю каких героев в Монголии
you know
вы знаете
Khan Well, this is not this is already an old old type
Хан Ну это не это уже давний давний типа
A more modern
А современнее
Ulan bater Ulan bater is the
Улан батер Улан батер - это
capital it is a hero no also also like
столица это герой нет также также как
Ulan-ud in Buryatia Ulan is a settlement
Улан уд в Бурятии Улан - Это поселение
as a city tell me it is
как город скажите
not a hero It is a capital look well Why are
не геро Это столи хорошо смотри Почему
you of all the
вы из всех
neighbors interested in only you
соседей вам интересно именно только
hero of Ukraine
герой Украины
Why is the thing that we are not interested in the hero of
Почему дело вот в чём нам не герой
Ukraine but in the politics of the country
Украины интересен а политика страны
that is trying to
которая пытается вот этого
say this hero
героя как сказать
well against us you see father I will wave
ну против нас вот понимаете батька махну
here I am a real historian  I know the history of
вот я реальный историк Я знаю историю
Ukraine and other things. I am also a historian. I have
Украины и прочие дела Я тоже историк у
18 years of practice. In 2 years I will be
меня 18 лет практики через 2 года будет
20. I defended my dissertation. I am writing a
двадцатом диссертацию защитил пишу
doctoral dissertation. Okay, God, God to all. Father
докторскую ладно бог см бог всем Батька
Makhno and others. Let's say Petliura
Махно и прочие там вот допустим Петлюра
and the rest. They fought, but you
там и остальные они воевали но вы же
chose yourself as a hero.  not you And to
выбрали себе в героя вернее не вы А
you, well, look I don't know, the
вам да ну смотрите Я вот не знаю вот у
Russians have
русских да
it all Let me tell you, don't
н вое Дайте дайте сказать не
interrupt, the thing is that your Styopa
перебивайте дело в том что ваш Стёпа
Bandera is not essentially a hero of
Бандера по сути не является героем
Ukraine, they explained to you that he is, like,
Украины вам объяснили что он как бы там
somewhere, you know, something  m what is your
чего-то где-то знаете в м в чём ваша
problem is that Bandera
проблема в том что в том что Бандера
if
если
he is a manipulative
это манипулятивный
character he is not suitable for Russians and
персонаж он и русским не подходит и
not suitable for Belarusians and not
белорусам не подходит и полякам не
suitable for Poles that is you have
подходит то есть у вас
a country on top
страна сверху
Belarus on the right
Беларусь справа
Russia on the left you have Poland and not counting
Россия слева у вас Польша да не считая
Moldova and there you go  they consider such a
Молдавии и вот вам вам причисляют такого
Bandera a hero And I will tell you why I will tell you
бандеру геро А я скажу почему я скажу
why Because he suits Hungary
почему Потому что он подходит Венгрии
Bandera suits Hungary because he was
Бандера подходит Венгрии потому что он
born in the Austro-Hungarian Empire
родился в австро-венгерской Империи
Hungary suits Hungary  Bandera is suitable
Венгрии подходит Венгрии подходит
for Hungarians we made Bandera
Бандера для венгров мы сделали бандеру
Everything is clear clear but in case of
Всё чётко чётко но в случае
something
чего
against your
против вашего
idol so it will be Poland will
этого идола так будет Польша будет
be Belarus will be Russia so it is today
Беларусь будет Россия так так сегодня
Russia If suddenly something
Россия Если вдруг чего-нибудь то вам
then you will remember Poland Bandera
потом Польша будет вспоминать бандеро
so well What difference does it make to us none
так хорошо Вам какая разница нам никакой
Well  so you are so worried
не Ну вот вы так короче переживаете
Will Poland be or not what
Будет ли Польше не будет какая вам
difference does it make to you the relationship between Poland and
разница отношения Польши и
Ukraine for us there is none at all in
Украины для нас никакой вообще в
principle there is you are watching You
принципе нет есть вы же смотрите Вы
know you are analyzing something for you
знаете вы там что-то анализирует для вас
this is a sore subject And why is it
это больная тема А почему
so no question at all Why are you
так вообще никакой вопрос Почему вы
Russian  made Lenin their
русские сделали Ленина своим
national
национальным
hero because Lenin he fought for don't
героем потому что Ленин он воевал за не
look for example Take Kotovsky
смотри вот например Возьмите Котовского
he fought RSA he fought But Lenin didn't
он воевал РСА он воевал А Ленин не
fight Why did you put Lenin you and
воевал Почему вы Ленину поставили вы и
Bandera were the leader and Bandera was the leader
Бандера был вождём и Бандера был вождём
wait a second Bandera was the leader
подожди в секунду Бандера был вождём
Bandera the leader Stepan Andreevich Bandera
Бандера вождь Степан Андреевич Бандера
leader of the organization of Ukrainian nationalists
вождь организации украинских националист
Lenin Lenin was born in
ун Ленин Ленин родился в
Ulyanovsk and Bandera was born in the old city of
Ульяновске а Бандера родился в старому у
Greno  Lenin was not born in Ulyanovsk but in Siberia you are a historian Well Simbir so God bless him Lenin was a recognized leader everyone recognized him Stalin Trotsky so Bandera was also this how is it uh leaders everyone recognized him too Yaroslav Stetsko Yaroslav Stetsko Yes Stepan Lenka everyone else recognized him territories of what and you Lenin was recognized on the territory of Soviet Russia Bandera was recognized on the territory of Yes Ukraine Armed Forces of Ukraine Bandera look Bandera was the leader Yes Ukrainian organization of Ukrainian nationalists Lenin was some kind of leader it is not clear some kind of some kind of Working class some kind of it is not clear at all abstract Well, look, why didn't Lenin fight for you? RS Kotovsky fought. Yes, Kolchak. Kolchak fought for you, for Mother Rus'. And you erected a monument to Lenin who didn't fight. Why do you understand that your Lenin? Well, he doesn't suit the Finns, or the Belarusians, or the Ukrainians, or Don't burden the Kazakhs  to the
грено Ленин не в Ульяновске родился а в
Azerbaijanis, not to the Mongols, not to the Chinese,
азербайджанцам ни монголам ни китайцам
not to the Japanese, in case of anything, you will have claims against you
ни японцам в случае чего к вам будут
on Lenin from all your
претензии по Ленину от всех ваших
neighbors, you understand, everything is
соседей понимаешь Всё
clear, that's what Lenin did for you,
чётко вот что сделал Ленин для вас
look, Lenin destroyed the Russian
Смотри Ленин вам развалил Российскую
Empire for you, Lenin lost Yes, part of Poland,
империю Ленин потерял Да часть Польши
part of
часть
Ukraine, Lenin lost everything, the world war
Украины Ленин всё проиграл мировую войну
that the Tsar should  was to win
которую царь должен был выиграть
and
и
signed a treaty
подписали договор
Yes the French with the Germans already without the
Да французы с немцы уже без царя
Russian Tsar the French for themselves Yes and the British
русского французы себе Да и британцы
America appropriated the victory in the First
Америка присвоили победу в Первой
World War Although the Russian people put
мировой войне Хотя русские люди положили
so much
столько
into so much Yes remember the Brusilov breakthrough
в столько Да Брусиловский прорыв помните
remember How much it cost there were a lot of victims
помните Сколько стоило жертв очень много
and then what came when
а потом что пришёл когда
uh Russia was  together with others
ээ россиюшка была вместе с другими
already half a step away from victory over Germany what
уже полушаге от победы над Германией что
did Lenin do recalled the troops said No
сделал Ленин отозвал войска сказал Нет
we are not fighting we will build the proletariat
мы не воюем мы будем строить пролетариат
He about your country then what did
Он про вашу страну потом что сделал
Lenin do he took invented Ukraine
Ленин он взял придумал Украину вам
invented you Belarus invented all these
придумал Беларусь придумал все эти
Republics you have Tatarstan
Республики у вас татарста
Uzbekistan these in short Dagestan everything
Узбекистан эти короче Дагестан всё это
Lenin came up with all this before that you had the
всё Ленин придумал до этого у вас была
Empire and Lenin thought of
Империя Империя а Ленин взял подумывал
everything for you  Lenin, you're now going to clean up the mess of
всё Ленин вы сейчас расхлёбывать
his monuments Yes, one question, let me
ему памятники Да один вопрос давай
resolve
разрешаю
the alov and Lenin will
алов и Ленин
explain that Brusilov Yes, he killed so many
объясню что Брусилов Да положил столько
Russian soldiers Yes, in these meaty assaults And
русских солдат Да в этих мясных штурма А
Lenin with his gang, the left sector,
Ленин со своей бандой левый сектор
came, nullified all the achievements of the Russian
пришёл обнулил все достижения русского
soldier and withdrew all troops from the fronts of the
солдата и отвёл все войска с фронтов
First World War and  said we
первой мировой войны и сказал мы не
will no longer participate in these
будем больше участвовать в этих
imperialist and all Germany
империалистический и всё Германия
signed the capitulation without the participation of the
подписала капитуляцию без участия
Russian Empire and that is the
Российской империи а то есть бищ
Soviet Union Soviet Russia because
Советского Союза Советской России потому
not the Soviet Union therefore remained
что не Советский Союз потому остал
Soviet Russia
Советская Россия
simply Lenin your history Lenin and so and so
просто Ленин вашу историю Ленин итак
Brusilov and Lenin are connected Yes and
итак Брусилов и Ленин связаны Да а
Suvorov and  for example Kutuzov
Суворов и например Кутузов
no no
нет нет
Why was Suvorov in some cases Kutuzov
Почему Суворов в одних делах был Кутузов
in others and
в других а
Brusilov so Brusilov is Brusilov A
Брусилов так Брусилов это Брусилов
contemporary of Lenin Yes, Brusilov
Современник Ленина Да как раз Брусилов
fought for the Empire And Lenin the Empire that's
воевал за Империю А Ленин Империю вот и
all in what year look Brusilov is
всё в каком году смотри Брусилов - это
like Prigozhin you understand how Prigozhin
как Пригожин понимаешь как Пригожин
he with his assault
он своим штурмом мясным пробивал поступ
meaty broke through the empire's advance and Lenin just took and everything look now a very simple question a very simple question uh Orthodoxy - is it Rus' or not Rus' Orthodoxy No, it's not an integral part of Russian statehood True Well it's like scratching with fasteners wait wait wait Orthodoxy and Rus' is like you understand winter like winter And for example the Indians look again I repeat look the Russian Orthodox Church Is it one of the pillars of the Russian state or not I don't really understand tell me how this is equal to us yes or no Russian Orthodox Church Is it one of the pillars Russian state Yes or no Yes yes Lenin banned and destroyed the Russian Orthodox Church yes or no Lenin Yes it was that is look there are two very simple chains of two statements Russian Orthodox Church from the Russian state Lenin banned and destroyed the Russian Orthodox Church result Lenin banned and destroyed one of the pillars of the Russian state and you erected monuments to him in every city of yours you are on him  Red Square in the heart of the
городе вы ему на Красной Площади в серце
Russian state they erected a
Русского государства поставили
temple Maley, not a Russian word called
храм Малей не русским словом названным
Negrey, it still lies there and everyone goes to
Негрей лежит до сих пор и все ходят к
it as if to worship the relics of
нему как на поклонение на мощ ты
this one who took and
посмотреть этого который взял и
destroyed the God-fighter, he was a God-fighter, the
уничтожил богоборец он был богоборец
Antichrist, and you
антихрист и вы про российскую
killed and shot the autocrat about the Russian state
державу убили расстреляли самодержца
as a half  Where did you all crawl out from then
как полу Откуда вы повылазили потом
and take
все и взяли
government portfolios otherwise there will be a failure
государственные портфели иначе сбой
dialogue we will conduct a dialogue Now wait
диалог будем вести диалог Сейчас подожди
I will continue for a second I will trust the sermon and this and
я прод секунды я довер проповедь и это и
they took and crawled out and said that a cook
взяли вылезли и сказали что кухарка
can govern a state a sin is a sin
может управлять державой грех это грех
let it be
дава
combined here the Supreme Court now told
сочетается вот ВС сечас рассказал
Brusilov Lenin all other affairs I  I
Брусилов Ленин все остальные дела Я же
told you the Great Russian Empire The
сказал Великую Российскую империю
legacy of the ancient ru we Russian empire
Наследие древней ру мы российскую импе
here is a [ __ ] question If why are you putting up monuments to the main
вот сри вопрос Если вы зачем вы главного
petitioner of the empire the main protester of the empire
просителя империи главного проте империи
Why
ставите памятники Зачем
because Russia was is and will be so
потому что Россия была есть и будет так
And why did you put up a monument to the one who
А зачем вы поставили памятник тому кто
destroyed Russia bled it dry
уничтожал Россию обескровил её
beheaded the tsar Here  you you  you claim
обезглавил царя Вот ты Ты утверждаешь
that he does not exist and Russia has empires and that's
что его нет а России есть империи есть и
all there is empires there is no empire because there cannot
всё есть империи нет потому что не может
be an empire without an emperor the emperor is
быть империи без императора императора
appointed by God and the people exist You
назначает Бог а народ Существую Ты мне
explain to me why I am
объясни почему я
ordinary Putin you do not have an empire because there
обычный Путина империи у вас нет потому
is no empire without an emperor the
что не существует империи без императора
emperor is the anointed one  God's power
император - это помазанник Божий власть
is given to the emperor by God by right of
императору даётся Богом по праву
birth and not by the people by right of election the
рождения а не народом по праву выборов
president can never be an emperor the
президент никогда не может быть импера
emperor is the inspiration of God on
император это воодушевление Бога на
Earth there is the Russian
Земле есть Российская
Federation I
Федерация Я
exist and you tell me that
существую и ты мне Рассказываю что у
I don't have you exist but there is no empire the empire
меня нет ты есть а империи нету Империя
collapsed there is now a Federation
развалилась есть теперь Федерация
what
какая-то
-there is no empire because there is no
Т импе нет империи потому что нет
emperor there is no empire without an
императора не существует империи без
emperor there are no empires without an
императора не существуют империи без
emperor conservatories without a
императора консерватории без
conservative observatories without an
консерватора обсерватории без
observatory That is, you think that a
обсерватора То есть ты считаешь что
conservatory is a canned food
консерватория - это
No, the conservatory is at the head
консерва Нет во главе консерватория
Look, at the head of the observatory is an
Смотри во главе обсерватории стоит
observatory an observer at the head of the
обсерватор наблюдатель во главе
conservatory is  conservative who
консерватории стоит консерватор который
makes canned food And at the
консервы делает А во
head of the empire is the emperor there is no
главе империи стоит император нету
emperor there is no empire this is the base of the
императора нету империи это база
Russian empire No there is a Federation
Российской империи Нет есть Федерация
Look,
Смотри вот пе
you are not an emperor, but who are you in the Federation? You are a
импер а в Федерации вы кто Вы Феде вы
federation, not an emperor. Who are you? Well, a resident of the Federation, who is a federation, a
ты кто Ну житель Федерации кто федера
resident of the Republic, a republican.
житель Республики республиканец
Well, let's move on. I understand correctly.
Ну давай поехали дальше я правильно поня
If only the
еслиб
Federation had a federation. The Federation is not an empire. Can I
Феде Федерация - это не Империя Можно я
still howl? Can I?
пока выю можно можно
Let's ask a question. How?  you are a person who
Давай вопрос Как вы человека который взя
exchanged the Empire for some union and
променял Империю на какой-то союз а
then also Yeltsin who destroyed the union
потом ещё и Ельцин который развалил союз
and you built him a fake Yeltsin Center in
а вы ему построили лый ельцин-центр в
Yekaterinburg
Екатеринбурге
which destroyed your Soviet
который развалил ваш Советский
Union you put up a monument to Lenin who
Союз вы ставите памятник Ленину который
destroyed the Russian Empire and you put up
развалил Российскую империю И ставите
a monument to Yeltsin yes come on Wait
памятник е ельцину да давай Подожди
Good question Generally a great
Хороший вопрос Вообще Великолепный
question I think that
вопрос я думаю что вот
this
это
building I hope
здани Надеюсь скоро
will soon be well, as it were,
будет ну как
cleaned up because it is there look you
убора потому что оно есть смотри вы
None of you Russians came out to the
Никто из вас из россиян не вышел На
rally demanding the removal of the Yeltsin Center
митинг с требованием убрать Ельцин центр
Am all the years all the years it is there and you And
Ам все года все года он там есть и вы А
why  you because he destroyed your
зачем ты потому что он разрушил ваш
Soviet Union and let the other republics
Советский Союз дал другим республикам
escape with it  Gorbachev and all
убежать вместе с горбачёвым и всё
and you bowed to him to
а вы ему поклонясь
whom in Samara El
кому в Самаре ель
va None of the Russians spoke out against
ва Никто из россиян не выступил против
it
ен
myself
сама
I
я
generally
вообще
and today it is a simple pro
и на сегодняшний день это простой проу
kom the
ком
matter is the following I can explain to you
дело в следующем я тебе могу пояснить
Why is this happening EU belt belt Yes
Почему происходит такое ЕС пояс пояс Да
if you listen Let's take an interesting case
если ты послушаешь Давай интересно дело
in the next VV Putin is a man of
в следующем ВВ Путин человек
his word and he has a quirk
слово и у него есть бзик
he is responsible for his bazaar and he once
он отвечает за базар и Он когда-то
promised this whole family
пообещал вот этой всей семье
that they would not be touched and he still
е что их не тронут и до сих пор он
keeps his word and you know there is a point in this
держит слово И знаешь в этом есть смысл
because the whole world sees that he  can
потому что весь мир видит что он может
say if you join, for example, the OKB, they
сказать если вы вступите например в ОКБ
won't touch you because I still do
вас не тронут потому что я до сих пор
n't touch the Yelny Center for you, this is a
вот ельн цент не трогаю для вас это
disaster for the West. The problem is that
беда для Запада Проблема в том что это
there's a five-story building or how many
вот там пятиэтажка или сколько там
buildings there are, there's
зданий там
a war there, it exists. Well, understand, for
война она существует Ну пойми вот для
Russia this is  how to say well like a
России это как сказать ну как бы типа
pimple or something on the body Well it's painful but it
прыщик что ли на теле Ну болезненно но
doesn't affect the body and for Putin for
на организм не влияет а для Путина для
Putin and this is a promise he is a [ __ ]
Путина и это обещание он он пися той же
and Sobchak
и Собчак
Well you know we have
Ну знаешь у нас
such a Sobchak she is
такая Собчак она орёт
she yells at she swears she has
в она матерится она носит
inviolable power Why Because Putin
неприкосновенная Почему Потому что Путин
once promised his boss not to touch
когда-то своему шефу пообещал не трогать
anyone and he holds this you see in the World
никого и он эту держит понимаешь в ЧМ
Cup and the whole world understands that if Vova
дело а весь мир понимает что если Вова
said I am
сказал я
responsible then you don't even have to
отвечаю то за это можно даже не
worry about it  don't touch your
переживать из-за этого не трогают ваш
this center this Sobchak and other things but
этот центр эту Собчак и прочие дела но
for the time being understand the time will come
до поры до времени пойми настанет время
when Putin will cover all
когда Путин накроет всех
these there and everything will be thread by thread people
этих там и всё будет по нитку народ
understand that these all
понимает что эти все
Therefore you don't delude yourself too much the
Поэтому вы-то сильно не обольщайтесь
problem is not what is happening there
проблема не в том что там что происходит
in  the problem is global Putin today is
в проблема в глобальном Путин сегодня
not fighting with your five-story
воюет не с вашим пятиэтажных
building but he is fighting with the West not with
зданием а он воюет с западом не с
Ukraine and your flag behind you does
Украиной и флаг твой за тобой вообще
not mean anything at all by and large
ничего не значит по большому счёту
in
в
principle and Putin is the greatest president the
принципе и Путин величайший президентша
question is look if Putin is responsible for
вопрос смотри если Путин так отвечает за
his bazaar Putin publicly to the Russian
свой базар Путин публично российскому
people  promised that the retirement age
народу пообещал что пенсионный возраст
would not be raised but it was raised How does it
поднимать не будут но поднял Как так
happen
получается
He yes
Он
yes so Putin is responsible for the bazaar he is
да так Путин же за базар отвечает
responsible he
отвечает
is responsible so that is Putin Yeltsin promised the center
отвечает так то есть Путин Ельцин центру
not to touch Sobchak promised not to
пообещал не трогает Собчак пообещал не
touch And he promised the Russian people not to
трогать А русскому народу пообещал не
raise the retirement age,
поднимать пенсионный возраст
but he
а
raised it And why is Putin doing this to some people?
поднял А почему так Путин неким людям
Dear sir, he promises and keeps his word, but he doesn't give a
Уважаемый обещает и держит слово а на
damn about the Russian people
русский народ с большой колокольни
because it's not about
потому что речь не о
the people, it's about
народе а речь о
what exists in this world,
том что в этом мире
you know how Well, most likely,
существует знаешь как Ну скорее всего
probably
наверно
three
три
Anglo-Saxons, Slavs
англосаксы славяне
and Chinese, roughly
и китайцы грубо
speaking, you know, in the World Cup, the war is
говоря знаешь в ЧМ дело война это идёт
not
не
about some
за какие там
[applause]
[аплодисменты]
or pension funds, but about existence, and
либо пенсионные фонды а существование и
today the Anglo-Saxons are against
сегодня англосаксы оказались против
China and the Slavs, and today we are talking about the
Китай и славян и сегодня речь идёт о
destruction of
уничтожении
the Anglo-Saxons, the destruction of
англосаксов уничтожении
the Sak, the whole world for the last 500
сак весь мир последние 500
years, I understand  I'm not so interested in the
лет я понял меня уже не так интересует
question of Putin's words and his retirement
вопрос слова Путина и его пенсионного
age everything is clear there yes it's possible for the Russian
возраста там всё понятно да на русский
people The question is different in this
народ можно Вопрос в другом в этой
triad on which the world rests Anglo-Saxons
триаде на которой держится мир англосакс
Slavs and China
славяне и Китай
for example Turks Kazakhs Syrians
отно например турки казахи сирийцы
Good question
Хороший вопрос
Listen seriously Good question I'll just
Слушай серьёзно Хороший вопрос Просто я
wash them and  They don't approach the Chinese and the
смою они и к китайцам не подходят и к
Slavs and they don't seem to be Anglo-Saxons. Oh,
славянам и вроде как бы не англосаксы Да
by the way, I forgot to add that And by the way,
кстати ещё забыл добавить и ста И кстати
this
это
applies to Brazilians.  Argentina all
касается бразильцев аргентину всех
the rest These are Spanish-Saxons Brazilians all the
остальных Это испано саксы бразильцы вся
Portuguese Argentines this is all Spanish-
португальцы аргентинцы это всё испано
Saxons are called here are Anglo-Saxons They
саксы называются вот есть англосаксы Они
captured North America Spanish-Saxons The
захватили Северную Америку испано саксы
South
Южные
captured and Syrians Kazakhs
захватили а а сирийцы казахи
Turks
турки
Azerbaijanis Turkmens Iranians
азербайджанцы туркмены иранцы
Jews this to which pole of power does it belong
евреи это к какому полюсу силы относится
Anglo-Saxons Chinese Slavs not Spanish
англосаксы китайцы славяне не испанок
Who are
Кто
they this
они это
between
меж
what is it called
что это называется
between Pony That is, I will now try to
между Поня То есть я сейчас попробую
explain my understanding this is not a fact you
объяснить моё понимание это не факт это
understand well
понимаешь
let's do it this way if honestly here it is
ну давай так вот если честно вотча нем
Well, how are we talking seriously we are not bantering
Ну как мы же серьёзно говорим мы не стеб
Yes yes yes
Да да
Just imagine Well, how are the guys in the
да Вот прикинь Ну ну как бы пацаны в
area Here are the authorities  one, two, three and
районе Вот есть авторитеты раздватри и
a bunch of them, well, like,
куча там ну как
here are the Arabs in their time, in their time, They
вот арабы в своё время в своё время Они
could have become authoritative, but they didn’t
могли бы стать авторитетными но у них не
succeed, they missed it sometime. They
получилось они упустили когда-то Они не
couldn’t, and today they have to choose
смогли и сегодня они должны выбрать
one of the three, America, Russia, or
кого-то из трёх Америку Россию или
China, these  here are all the rest,
Китай вот эти вот все вот остальные
I listed them, they should stick it to someone and
перечислил они должны кому-то прилепи и
they  they rush about because it is really visible
они мечутся потому что это реально видно
they are going back and
они и туда и
forth understand how this is even possible Here is
сюда пойми как это вообще возможно Вот
this in the
это
yard honestly, here and
дворе честно слово вот и на сегодняшний
today there is a tightening up going on, you understand, today there
день идёт понимаешь на сегодняшний день
is a tightening up going on, that is, Russia is tightening
идёт подтяжка то есть Россия подтягивает
itself up Here, notice, it is clearly visible Brix
себе Вот Заметь это же чётко видно Брикс
was created
создали
Brix is ​​like this  once collect these I
Брикс это вот как раз собрать вот эти я
understood I just Look I just don't quite
понял Я просто Смотри я просто не совсем
understand I want to understand Which peoples
разобраться Я хочу понять Какие народы к
belong to what Well Slavs Sak is us
чему относятся Ну славяна сак это мы
China Sak Sax Hispano Saxons and still
Китай Сак сакс испано саксы а всё-таки
Turks this is to which pole do
турки это к какому полюсу относятся
Turks belong not Well let's go they got lost in
турки не Ну давайте се они потерялись в
their time they They wanted you know how they
своё время они Они хотели знаешь как они
wanted and to plant on Well
хотели и насадить на Ну
in Russian you know What a tricky thing that
по-русски понимаешь Какая хитрая вещь то
is There are Well like
есть Есть Ну типа
Jews it is generally separate that is
евреев это вообще отдель то есть
you know
понимаешь
there are authoritative guys and
существуют пацаны авторитетные и
there are those who are And today
существуют те которые тся И вот сегодня
there are three nations here China Russia and
есть три нации вот Китай Россия и
America Anglo-Saxons Well Anglo-Saxons yes this is
Америка англосаксы Ну англосаксы да это
England But the French today Germans
Англия А вот французы вот сегодня немцы
they in their
они в своё
time being to
врем будучи к
the Anglo-Saxons what is the problem of the Germans the
англосакс в чём проблема германцев
Germans
германцы
are the people who in their time  time
это это люди которые в своё время
made friends with the aces and enough well they
подружились с асами и достаточно ну они
VS time fought A small question And what
ВС время воевали Маленький вопрос А что
does Anglo-Saxons mean Anglo it is clear
означает англосаксы англо это понятно
it is from England And
это из Англии А
Saxons Anglo-Saxons are
саксы англосаксы - это
English-speaking SAK is lingual means Yes
англоязычные сак это язычные означает Да
wait wait there
подожди подожди
were strong Well let's say
было сильных Ну скажем
so the center is the French
так центра это французы
Ruriks wait I don't know the
рюрики подожди не знаю
French English  and the Germans and
французы англичане и немцы а
Austria is Herman the Austro-Hungarian
Австрия это Герман австро-венгерская
Empire was No it's
империя была Нет это
not Remember wait
не Вспомни подожди
but they are there you understand
себе но они там понимаешь
They are Romans stop and the Romans Yes wait you let me let me
Они Римляне стоп а Римляне Да подожди ты
Greeks let me say let me say
дай дай греки дай сказать-то дай сказать
to the end look in Europe there were very
до конца смотри в Европе было очень
few many forces Spaniards Portuguese  the
несколько много сил Испанцы португальцы
French the Germans
французы немцы
the English the Italians and at different times at
англичане итальянцы и в разное время в
different times even Macke
разное время даже Маке
Alexander the Great
Александр Македонский
remember Well there was such a thing it was like this
помнишь Ну было такое дело было так вот
at different times all these guys you
в разные времена вот эти вот все пацаны
know like today our yard is the coolest
знаешь как сегодня наш двор самый крутой
Zavra your yard is the coolest so this is
Завра ваш двор самый крутой так вот это
all this
вся вот это
in  Cook, cook, cook, cook and they are
в Варись варилась варись варись и они
still there  since many times they two
пока там со многих времён они две
things
вещи
Asia
Азию
Russia and America that is they missed a little
Россию и Америку то есть они маленько
they committed dd so the question is not
упустили они совершили дди так вопрос не
me just want I am also interested in philology
я просто хочу я ещё увлекаюсь филологией
I always look into the essence of words in etymology
Я всегда смотрю в суть слов в этимологию
What is Anglo-Saxon Angla - it is clear
Что такое англосакс англа - это Понятно
Because from England And
Потому что из Англии А
you are Saxons  the same historian who are the Saxons
саксы вы же историк кто такие саксы
Saxons Saxons Saxons Who are the Saxons where are
саксы саксы саксы Кто такие саксы откуда
they from Saxony Yes these are Germanic
они из саксонии Да это германские
tribes that came from Saxony from the territory of
племена которые из саксонии с территории
modern Germany yes to the
современной Германии пришли да на
British
британский
Come on I'm a historian I'm telling you 18 years of
Давай я историк Я же тебе говорю 18 лет
practice in 2 years I'll be a
практики через 2 года буду
dch
дч
neri if you don't know k  such Saxons
нери если не знаешь к такие сакс
Saxons are also Germans Germans
саксы это же есть немцы германцы
this is a common name so look
это общее название так смотри Кто такие
Who are the Saxons Look who are the Saxons Read
саксы Посмотри кто такие саксы Прочитай
not Saxons Read Who are the
не саксы Прочитай Кто такие
Saxons this is a common name Read Saxons
саксы это общие название Прочитай саксы
who are I am not speaking English And Saxons who
кто такие я говорю не Анг А саксы кто
are the
такие
Saxons now Let's
саксы сейчас Давай
ask Let's ask
спросим Давай спросим
the ancient Germanic
древнегерманское
tribe  yes, that is it  Germans so
племя вот да то есть это германцы так
Germans you say that the Germans
германцы ты говоришь что германцы
sold out to the Anglo-Saxons the Germans are the
продались англосакс германцы это и есть
Anglo-Saxons didn't say those Okay I'll
англосакс не говорил те Ладно я тебе
tell you as a historian Look the Anglo-Saxons
расскажу как историк Смотри англосаксы
are the great conde of the
это великая конде
Germanic tribes they united under the
германских плем они объединились под
leadership of Clovis the Great and
предводительством хлодвига Великого и
stopped the blood his wife Gertrude oh
остановили кровную его жена Гертруда ой
his daughter Gertrude Yes she married
его дочь Гертруда Да вышла замуж за
Richard the Lionheart and after that
Ричарда Львиное сердце и после этого на
forever and ever there was the Great
вечные было великое
Anglo-Saxon Commonwealth from there and
англосаксонское Содружество оттуда и
Ponsa Herman all decided to challenge the
понса Герман все реши бросить вызов
Great Anglo-Saxon Union Yes and Paul
Великому англосаксонском Союзу Да и пол
against Britain for which he paid And
против Британии за что и поплатился А
now the Anglo-Saxons are all right NATO
теперь англосаксы всё нормально НАТО это
is the Great Anglo-Saxon Union
и есть Великий англосаксонский Союз туда
all the Slavs are included Yes
входят все славяне Да
all Romans all Greeks all Europe This is what
все Римляне все греки вся Европа Вот это
Anglo-Saxons are like come on let's
есть англосакс давай
mix up the porridge why did you burp
перемешивается чего ты отрыжку сделал
come on tell the
да давай
story
рассказ
look today
смотри на сегодняшний день на
today we have a very simple
сегодняшний день мы имеем очень простую
thing war between all these  you
вещь войну вот между вот этими всеми вот
know Well
понимаешь Ну
today
сегодня на сам
I myself sometimes look at this thing this is
вот я вот иногда гляжу на это дело это
purely boyish Here today one
вот чисто пацанское Вот вот сегодня один
yard wins tomorrow another today
двор выигрывает завтра другой сегодня
Mishka was the coolest among us then
Мишка был у нас самый крутой потом его
they put him in jail or killed him there and Vaska grew up and
посадили или Там убили и Васька вырос и
so on Look what we have on
так далее Вот смотри что мы имеем на
today today we have Vova
день на сегодняшний день мы имеем Вову
Putin who is really starting to rule
Путина который реально начинает рулить
the world
миром
here he is
вот он потому
because firstly he promises
что первое первое он обещает
equality secondly he plays on the fact that
равноправие второе он играет на том что
those who used to rule the world they are here in
вот те кто раньше рулил миром они вот
the sixties seventies here is
шестидесятые семидесятые годы вот
America it was Well really
Америка это было Ну реально вот
well the center of the world  the universe and other things
ну Центр мира вселенной и прочие дела
really really answer but it was the
реально реально отвечаю но это было
sixties seventies and here he is
шестидесятый семидесятые годы и вот он
Putin today says guys Today
он Путин сегодня говорит ребята Сегодня
I promise you this this this this And
я вам обещаю вот это вот это вот это А
those who were there in the sixties seventies
те кто там в шестидесятые семидесятые
Well let's say
годы Ну скажем так
they ruled today
рулил они сегодня
and got carried away yeah yeah yeah  really really well
а заигрались да да ну реально реально
agree Well you're a man and I'm a
вот ну согласись Ну вот ты мужик и я
man Yeah tell me we're both men
мужик Угу скажи оба мы мужики
Yeah Tell me how can you admit it Well
Угу Скажи ну как можно допуска вот Вот
like this I'm watching a movie Yes, a movie and
как вот вот вот смотрю кино Да кино и
they
там
show Prince
показывают князя
Vladimir like that  he was black, that's it,
Владимира так он же был чернокожий
that's it, he was black, the
вот вот Вот так он чернокожий был кня
historical Prince Vladimir Well, really
Владимир исторический Ну действительно
Well, so what's
Ну так в чём
the problem, that's it, that's it, that's it, that's all about
проблема так вот Вот это вся по поводу
Prince Vladimir being black And that
что князь Владимир был чернокожий И что
in every movie you should not swear
в каждом кино должен бы можешь не матюка
every other word, stupidly every other word
через каждое слово тупо через
Why  why should there be
ка Почему почему должна быть
tolerance I mean what is the
толерантность В смысле что
game Why listen watch I don't understand at all What does
игра Почему слушай смотри я вообще не
it have to do with you all the films you want to
понимаю Причём тут вы се какие хотите
make What why do you
фильмы так снимаете Какая зачем вы
watch Hollywood films why do you
смотрите голливудские фильмы зачем вы
watch these films with the black prince
смотрите эти фильмы с чернокожим князем
Vladimir who makes you go to them Do
Владимиром кто вас заставляет на них
you have your own film studio
ходить У вас есть своя киностудия
Mosfilm which makes wonderful
Мосфильм которая снимает прекрасные
films there with light steam operations
фильмы там с лёгким паром операции
watch them why do you watch these summer
смотрите их зачем вы смотрите эти летные
western films
западные фильмы
you go to the cinema pay money
Вы ходите В кинотеат платите деньги
so that these NATO films are filmed again
чтобы эти натовские фильмы снова снимали
why do you listen man The thing is that when they
Зачем слы мужик Дело в том что когда нам
started showing us that for example
начали показывать Что например
some prince Yaroslav or  there is
какого-нибудь князя Ярослава или там
someone playing and
кого-то играет и
each of us should be I am for you
нам каждой компании должен быть я тебе
it is even more scary look there is not only that
это ещё страшнее смотри есть мало того
you watched I watched Here is a New Year's
ты смотрел я смотрел Вот новогодний
film they showed in Ukraine Yes
фильм у нас в Украине показывали Да
prince  Yaroslav the Wise and Alexander Nevsky
князь Ярослав Мудрый и Александр Невский
were called that way Yes, that's how they were connected
так и назывался Да так вот их соединили
Do you know who plays Alexander Nevsky,
знаешь кто играет Александра Невского
who is the
кто женщина
Chinese
китайской
woman? We are showing a Hollywood film about Alexander Nevsky specifically so that the great and faithful prince Alexander is shown in the form of a plump Chinese woman Can you imagine that
женщины ты представляешь себе такое
Prince Alexander Nevsky  who defeated
Князь Александр Невский который разбил
the Teutons on the
тевтонов на
lake like you Russians now
озере как и и вы русские сейчас у вас
this film is also shown you
этот фильм тоже показывается у вас пошли
people went to the cinema and paid money
люди в кинотеатре и платят деньги
financed by Prince Nevsky Alexander
финансируется князь Невский Александр
you were the first to run NATO when the
вы первые побежали натовский когда
Soviet Union collapsed you Russians were the
развалился Советский Союз вы русские
first to run for jeans and chewing gum
первые Побежали за джинсами и жвачками
first Yes in Moscow  McDonald's opened
первый Да в Москве Макдональдс открылся
first in the Soviet Union back in the
первый в Советском Союзе ещё в
nineties what a line stood you
девяностом году очередь какая стояла ты
saw this yes photographs of the
видел это да фотографии очередь
McDonald's line Why did you suddenly run
McDonald's Почему вы побежали вдруг
Great Socialist power And as
Великая Социалистическая держава А как
soon as McDonald's opened So you stood in single file to eat
только открыли McDonald's Так вы гуськом
eat eat such a Russian word is called
есть есть такое русское слово называется
Morok Morok so to this day  you
Морок Морок так до сих пор у вас Морок
still have Morok Lenin
до сих пор Ленин в гробу
turned over in his grave Stalin just caught fire
перевернулся Сталин Просто воспламенился
you know
понимаешь
McDonald's My name is Father
Макдональдс Меня зовут отец
Andronicus here
Андроник вот
Well, it kind of enchants you and you
Ну как бы очаровывает ну тебя обт и ты
understand but the thing is the following Russian
понимаешь но дело в следующем русские
people today understand this Morok so here's the
люди сегодня этот морог понимают так вот
trick - what Morok is  who was
фишка - то в чём вот морог который был в
in Russia in the nineties with
девяностые годы в России с
chicken legs with friendship with this West and
окорочками с дружбой с этим западом
other things, today he is falling,
прочими делами он сегодня спадает
he just fell And the Russians say
он просто упал И россияне говорят
Listen,
Слышь
this is what is happening now and we
ты вот такая сейчас происходит и мы
started to fight
начали друг
each other, the Americans are just sitting and smiling,
друга просто американцы сидят и лыбу
they are really ly but they don’t understand
давят реально они лы но они не понимают
one thing  a simple thing a
одну простую вещь
very simple thing that today
очень простую вещь что сегодня
you scal thea name is father anro anro and I
ты скал тея зовут отец анро анро и я
Evgeniy m such your glasses your cap
Евгений м такие свои очки свою кепку
Take off Burbot we will put them back then we will say
Сними Налим мы их обратно потом скажем
Listen
Слушай
bro let's go
братан пошли
Aro
Аро
really With all my
реально От всей
heart for
души за
their this When for us here a
их вот эту Когда нам вот
Chinese woman plays our prince
китаянка играет нашего князя
Yaroslav  Alexander
Ярослава Александра
Nevsky in the world
Невского в миру
Prokhorov notice us tried
Прохоров заметь нас пытались
good question question look if this  The
хорош вопрос вопрос смотри если этот
darkness slept why are you now Use
Морок спал почему сейчас вы Пользуйтесь
all NATO Anglo-Saxon phone
всем натовский англосаксонский телефон у
you have
вас
Anglo-Saxon programs all on
англосаксонские программки все на
phones look No when the council
телефонах смотри Нет когда совет
actually Soviet man Okay he
собственно Советский человек Ладно он
stood from his in McDonald's and you are now
стоял из своей в McDonald's а вы сейчас
American Yes Bill Gates sees all
американский Да Билл Гейтс видит все
your movements You
ваши передвижения Вы со своими
go everywhere with your phones with sensors  all
телефонами с датчиками ходите всюду все
your Generals military you all
ваши Генералы военные вы всё
movement you you have a chip the Number of
передвижение вас у вас чип есть Число
the Beast is now with you you with a chip which
зверя теперь с вами вы с чипом который
is a phone you go everywhere to the toilet with a
есть телефон ходите всюду в туалет с
chip sleep with a chip on a trip with a chip the
чипом спите с чипом в поездку с чипом
Anglo-Saxons know everything about you you not only
англосаксы знают про вас всё вы не то
sold out to the Anglo-Saxons you became
что продались англосаксов вы стали
theirs  You have not created the Soviet
ихними Вы теперь не создали Советский
Union now, it had its own developments and its own telephone
Союз имел свои наработки да свой телефон
receiver which not a single Anglo-Saxon
трубочный который ни один англосакс не
could listen to. And you sold it for these
мог прослушать А вы продали за эти
buttons. And for this little screen with its e
кнопочки Да за эти экранчик со своими э
social networks with YouTube. And what do you All of you
соцсетями с ютубчик Да и что вы Всё вы
depend on when the Anglo-Saxons want to press
зависите когда англосаксы захотят нажму
a button and yours  the phones will stop
кнопочку и ваши телефоны перестанут
working, all the programs in them will stop
работать все программки в них перестанут
closing, they will be blocked and that's it  and your
закроются заблокируется и всё и ваши
phones will become bricks bricks
телефоны станут кирпичами кирпичами
It was intended and almost worked
Так было задумано и почти сработало
almost almost I won't
почти почти же не
press because we slipped at the last moment the
нажму потому что мы в последний момент
last
последний
moment the
момент
howl of the
соскользнула вой
phone Sams here is Samsung Korean
телефон Sams вот Samsung корейский
which is Anglo-Saxon South Korea Samsung
который англосакс Южная Корея Samsung
What operating system is there Android
Какая операционная там система Android
American from
американская от корпорации
Google corporation everything for today  moment yes
Google всё на сегодняшний момент да
Google corporation is completely
корпорация Google полностью
controlled by Sor Morgan and to
контролируется сором Морганом и к
szh Wait and since when was it
сжи Подожди а с ках пор это было
when you when your enemy and you
вот когда ты вот когда твой враг и ты
him Here I have today Here is this pipe
его Вот я сегодня имею Вот эту вот трубу
Yes seriously Well it is not our
Да ну серьёзно Ну она не нашей
Russian
российской
development you understand I understand
разработки понимаешь яс
today today  day we are
сегодняшний день сегодняшний день мы
forced because 30 years 30 years since the
вынуждены потому что 30 лет 30 лет с
nineties since the nineties Well
девяностого года с девяностого Ну
practically since the nineties
практически с девяностого
here is Gorbachev's
вот горбачевский
until yes
до да
30 years we kind of switched here
дено 30 лет мы как бы переходили вот на
and today it is impossible to jump back immediately
и сегодня перескочить назад сразу
and
невозможно и
Androids are dependent what are
Андроиды что там
iPhones but you understand what the problem is we don't
Айфоны но понимаешь в чём проблема мы не
we can jump off but we can't be punished
можем соскочить ну нас нельзя наказать
for this why why don't you need to be
за это вы зачем зачем вас не надо
punished you pay for these phones
наказывать вы платите за эти телефоны
like a tribute once  paid now Tribute to
как дань когда-то платили теперь Дань
Google corporation pay and Samsung
корпорации Google платите и Samsung
pay your money
платите свои деньги
earn
зарабо ве
everything they know everything about you and then
всё всё знают про вас они а потом на эти
they collect this money in Hollywood make
деньги собирают в Голливуде делают
films that Prince Alexander Nevsky
фильмы что Князь Александр Невский
woman Chinese Yes Listen The whole point is
женщина китаянка Да Послушай Всё дело
this it's like with the Mongol-Tatar
вот в чём это как с монголо татарским
yoke the same you understand  we need time
игом одинаково понимаешь нам нужно время
to shake off
чтобы стряхнуть
and send today Today we use
и послать сегодня Сегодня мы пользуемся
this prom because we have no choice but
этим пром потому что у нас выбора нет но
you know at the same time we use we
знаешь одновременно мы пользуемся мы
use
пользуемся
and they understand that we that is I
и они понимают что мы то есть я
understand correctly that the Anglo-Saxons
правильно понимаю что англосакс вас
put you on you have no opportunity to
посадили на у вас нет возможности пока
jump off yet but you hold on  Yes but in another
соскочить но Вы держитесь Да но в другое
VM understands that we are
ВМ понимает что мы соском с
seriously Listen really man really
серьёзно Слушай реально мужик реально
man but what is your serious name
мужик а вот как тебя серьёзно зовут
AC anro this is my real and you made my
АЦ анро это моё реальное и ты сделал мой
day man we started a conversation with
день мужик у нас началось разговор со
Stepan Bandera and ended with
Степаном Бандеры а закончил
hands called father an dronii My
руки зовут отец ан дрони Меня
name is come on  well just in life Yes really
зовут давай ну просто в жизни Да реально
father and drones
отец ан дрони
Lada Andrey come on Andrey not
Лады Андрей давай Андрей не
Android and drones you understand what the trick you are a
Андройд ан дрони понимаешь что фишка ты
Slav I  Slav and
славянин я славянин и у
we have And who are you I am a
нас А кто ты я
Jew you are a Jew Euro
еврей ты еврей евро
Saxon excellent
сакс отлично
Okay you know in the last
Ладно знаешь за последни
2 months probably for
наверно 2 месяца я
the first time I really talk to a person with
впервые реально с человеком говорю с
whom you can understand intellectually
которым можно понима интеллектуально
communicate Well with an intelligent person about all the
пообщаться Ну с умным человеком об все
smart
умные
Yes I am also Marvin By the way by nationality or
Да я тоже Марвин Кстати по нации или
this one how  you
этот как
know ask me I will
зна э спроси меня я те на этом языке
say any phrase in this language Well if it
скажу любую фразу Ну если она
exists ask me Mordi Tell me what
существует спроси я морди Скажи что
is ern
такое эрн
master what What is rzn master
мастор что Что такое рзн мастор
This is Earth master master master - This is
Это Земля мастер мастер мастер - Это
Earth Wait Yes how to how to say
Земля Подожди Да как бы как бы сказать
uh uh Erzya Earth will be
ээ ээ эрзянская Земля будет
free  Well, the Earth is a master and is
свободна Ну Земля мастро а
free
свободна
Damn, I live no longer exists the phrase
Блин я живу уже не существует фраза
freedom Yes, no The thing is that m
свобода Да нет Дело в том что м
Mordvin language it yes, yes, yes, well, think
Мордовский язык он дадада да ну подумай
Think up how to say Erzinskaya The Earth
Придумай вот как сказать эрзинская Земля
will be free Wait, wait, I'll
будет свободна Подожди подожди я
translate
переведу он
it integration into the Russian language is very
ин интеграция в русский язык очень
deep and master -  This is Earth, this is Must
глубока и мастер - Это Земля это ну Маст
Freedom m
Свобода м
No, I won’t translate it honestly, I won’t translate it
Нет не переведу честно не переведу
because I Well, I’m in  11 years old moved uh from a
потому что я Ну я в 11 лет переехал ээ с
Mordvin village I'm just
мордовского села я вот вот
uh settled me in a Mordvin village where people
э посели меня в мордовское село где люди
speak Moravian Well I
разговаривают на моравском языке Ну я
understand them but to talk I need
понимаю их но поговорить Мне нужно
about a day so that well I'm 50 years old already there
где-то сутки чтобы ну я 50 лет уже там
I'm 60 today and 10 years I was well  like
мне 60 сегодня и 10 лет я был ну как бы
mom and dad so and now Now the main
мама-папа так а теперь Теперь главный
question Are you piling something on me for
вопрос Вы мне что-то наваливать за
some Slavs And you turned out to be
каких-то славян А вы оказались
Erzya Yes at the
эрзя Да у
countess Yes so in this Great triad of
графин Да так то в этой Великой триаде
great peoples the Chinese Slavs and
великих народов китайцы славяне и
Anglo-Saxons who are the
англосаксы кто такие
Erzya this
эрзя это
component of
составляющее
Russia all not  endured
России всё не выдержал
ёr Zay
ёр Зай
oh just don't disappear don't disappear no no I'm
о только не исчезай не исчезай нене мне
interested then look uh wait I'll explain
интересно то смотри ээ подожди объясню
Let me explain my position
Давай мою позицию объясню
Yes the matter is as follows And in Russia in Russia there are
Да дело следующем А в России в России
more than 100 Nations of all sorts Morva Chuvashes
более 100 Наций всяких морва Чуваши люди
our people The fact is that we are all Russians and
наши Дело в том что мы все русские а
Russians are not Russian I am Russian  Well, as if by
русские не по я русский а Ну как бы по
affiliation or something, that's why it doesn't exist for us,
принадлежности что ли поэтому для нас не
when he asks where I'm from, I
существует вот когда спрашивает откуда я
say I'm Russian. And by  nationality I am
говорю я русский А по национальности Я
Mordvin that is for me Mordvin Russian
мордвин то есть для меня мордвин русский
it is the same and if you come to
это одинаково и вот если ты приедешь ко
me in the village where I was born or rather where I
мне в деревню где я родился вернее где я
grew up was born and everywhere then those
вырос родился и везде то те
with
с
Russian I am by nationality by nation in the
русский я по национальности по нации по
language of Erda Who is Inya
на языке эрда Кто такой Иня
Zor who is Inya
Зор кто Иня
Zor  I don't
Зор не
know this is
знаю это
the ruler no I don't know I'm so close
правитель не не знаю Я настолько близок
because I was born and raised in a Russian
потому что я родился и вырос в русском
village
селе
So do you know what it is You know what it
Так ты знаешь что такое Ты знаешь что
is cut bolya
такое срез боля
en like who is cheese bolya
ень как кто такой сыре боля
en No I don't know he and not Zor rzn he is
ень Нет не знаю он и не Зор рзн он
now
сейчас
fighting on the side  Ukraine against the
воюет на стороне Украины против
Russian Federation for freedom a
Российской Федерации за свободу
sign of protest against the displacement of the
знак протеста против вытеснения
Mordvin language no I don't know didn't even
мордовского языка нет не знаю даже не
know had no idea That's how it is That is you have
знал понятия не имел Вот так То есть ты
completely forgotten your people your family yes You are sitting You are
полностью забыл свой народ свой род да
sitting on a Russian Buka which
Сидишь Сидишь на русской Буке которая
is sitting on an Anglo-Saxon yes that is a
сидит на англосаксонской да то есть
matryoshka from you are sitting on  Russian and
матрёшка из ты сидишь на русской а
Russian sits on
русская сидит на
Anglo-Saxon and tells something
англосаксонской и что-то рассказываешь
philosophizes Yes Bandera shman
философствует Да Бандеры шман
Derysheva will
дерышева
not go will not go such a pitiful you
не пойдёт не пойдёт такая ты жалко
look  Look, you've lived your age
выглядишь Смотри ты прожил свой возраст
Yes, but you, wait, don't interrupt me, don't
Да но ты ты подожди не перебивай меня не
interrupt me when I interrupt if you
перебивай меня когда перебиваю я если
want us to continue talking Listen to
хочешь чтобы мы дальше говорили Послушай
me Otherwise, I'll switch Listen Now you're talking
меня Иначе я переключу Слушай Теперь ты
about Yes, you've lived a huge Yes, with salt If
про Да ты прожил огромный Да солью Если
you're going to interrupt now with salt Yes,
ты будешь перебивать сейчас солью Да
Listen, if you  do you want to talk to me
Послушай если ты хочешь со мной говорить
Listen listen and you write it down for me And you
Слушай слушай а ты мне записываешь А ты
lived lived a great life long that
прожил прожил Великую жизнь долгую то
is not great but a small but long
есть не Великую а маленькую но долгую
life did not acquire honor did not acquire conscience did not
жизнь не нажил чести не нажил совести не
acquire respect did not acquire intelligence reason you
нажил уважения не нажил ума розума ты
turned into such a simple walking
превратился в такой просто ходячий
sedentary stomach that lives out its
сидячий желудок который доживает свои
days and at least at the end of his life Noah
дни и хотя бы в конце своей Ной жизни
can see the light at the end of the tunnel and
может увидеть свет в конце тоннеля И
at least be a ray of light for his
хотя бы быть лучиком Света для своего
people and you sit instead of
народа а ты сидишь вместо того чтобы
finding out how the word freedom will be in your language
узнать как на языке твоём будет слово
you don’t know it you don’t know the word
свобода ты его не знаешь не знаешь слова
Freedom in your language
Свобода на своём языке не
you know you don't know the word country rzn
знаешь Ты не знаешь слово страна рзн
master What is this country rzn Earth you
мастор Да что это страна рзн Земля ты
are sitting there
сидишь там
in your
в своём
village the Russians have enslaved you and
там селении русские тебя поработили
are destroying you  your people and you sit and
уничтожают твой народ и ты сидишь
tell
рассказываешь
the Anglo-Saxons,
англосаксы
Germans, Portuguese,
немцы португальцы
Chinese You are
китайцы Ты
simply
просто
on the roads of
на дорогах
history
истории
and a very interesting dialogue, a very
и очень интересный диалог очень
indicative
показательный
dialogue, they started with
диалог начали с
Bandera and moved on to
Бандеры и перешли на очень
many short but very interesting
много недолгих но очень интересных
intellectual topics And you look at
интеллектуальных тем Да и вы смотрите
what explosions the English, Sak,
какие взрывы англы сак
Shmak, Erzya, Erzya people in Mordovia  Yes,
шмак человек эрзя эрзя в Мордовии Да
the people who have almost been overcome, almost
народность которую уже почти осилили поч
destroyed, are in Ukraine, there are
уничтожили есть в Украине
still conflicts and wars. There are these Erzya, uh, aggression, uh, including for understanding that only the fall of this great empire will give freedom to Ukraine and freedom to its people. And these walking ones are still sitting there.  and instead of thinking how
сих пор и вместо того чтобы подумать как
in his language Freedom how in his language
на его языке Свобода как на его языке
there people how how how all this roots spirit of
там народ как как как всё это корни дух
ancestors where is he yes he sits Anglo-Saxons
предков где он да он сидит англы саксы
Anglo-Saxons KhVE Rottweilers hot dogs peak
англо саксы ХВЕ ротвейлеры хот-доги пик
dogs that's all it was a very
доги вот и всё это был очень
indicative dialogue like subscribe
показательный диалог лайк подписка
comment and send this video to all your
коммент и скиньте это видео всем всем
friends it's very  intellectual
всем знакомым это очень интеллектуальный
conversation despite the humorous notes that
разговор несмотря на нотки юмора которые
were in it Glory to Ukraine
были в нём Слава Украине
subscribe to my Telegram right now
подпишись на ми Telegram прямо зараз
ovin and
овин а
popk this is very and very important YouTube Zaga
попк це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube Зага
us through scarg or in your ban and very
нас через скарг ор в твый бан и дуже
many videos I don't show to people at times I don't
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams Tom for
показуе информация про стрими Тому для
that we Mali operational links
того щоб ми Мали оперативний звязок
are written right now and while there in telegram
пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в телегра
okm video there is also interesting and useful
окм видео ще теж цикава и корисна
information and we will pon you operational
информация и мы пон вама пой оперативный
independently in that chi will show you about this
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine subscribe
YouTube Слава украини подпишись